# 陕西·西安
Xi’an, Shanxi
# 我坐在板凳上看人家吃面条
I’m watching them eating noodle while i’m on the wooden bench
# 每个人都是抱着一个不锈钢的盆
Everyone are holding a stainless steel pot
# 眼睁睁地看着他们 吃完了一整盆的面条
And they finished a whole pot of noodle
# 这陕西十大怪当中的碗盆难分开
It’s called “Bowls as big as basins” in Shanxi Ten strange customs
# 我今天算是见识到了
I saw it today
# 在陕西 尤其是关中地区
In Shanxi, expecilly in Guanzhong area
# 面食的吃法是多种多样
There are many ways to eat wheat flour products
# 如果你和我一样 来这边走一遭
If you come here just like me
# 怕是顿顿也不带重样的
You will not have same meals every day
# 蘸水面
Zhanshui noodle
# 我要了一个裤带蘸水面
I ordered a belt zhanshui noodle
# 阿姨先端来了一个小碗
The auntie brought a small bowl first
# 我说 不应该是面条像裤带吗 怎么碗这么小
I say, isn’t the noodle as long as the belt? Why is the bowl so small?
# 放近了一看才发现
I took a closer look and found out
# 这个只是蘸水
This is a Zhanshui(lit:”dipping soup”)
# 真正的面条在这里 用盆装的
The noodle actually is in the pot
# 面条真的是像裤带一样
The noodle looks like a belt
# 又宽 又粗
Wide and thick
# 关键这一盆才12块钱
The noodle in the pot only 12 yuan
# 别的地方加面条都是再加一些
Other place add some noodles when you order
# 这边面条是按根来加 一根3块钱
This place add every noodle for 3 yuan
# 端上来的除了面条之外 还有蘸水
They also serve noodles with zhanshui
# 能够看到蘸水红油油的
We can see zhanshui is red and oily
# 上面就是芝麻 辣子 香葱和蒜末
With sesame, spicy pepper, green onion, mashed garlic on the top
# 是西红柿卤子吧
Is that tomato soup?
# 你看 咱们在这边吃面 他们一般都会先剥一瓣蒜
You can see they will peel a garlic before eat noodle
# 但是我看里面是有蒜汁的
But I saw there is garlic sauce
# 咱们就不剥蒜了
So we don’t need to
# 直接是把面条扯进蘸水里
Just put noodle in the Zhanshui
# 面条真的是又长又宽
The noodle are very widely and thickly
# 我弄了老半天 这一根面条都没有到头
I can’t reach to the end of the noodle
# 这才是一根面
This is a noodle
# 这一根面就顶普通的一碗面
A noodle like this can compared with regular noodles
# 面条就像大面皮一样
Like “da mian pi”
# 蘸水真的是很有味
Zhanshui are very delicious
# 里面有西红柿的酸甜感
With sourness from tomatoes
# 还有芝麻和辣椒的香味
And fragment of sesame and spicy pepper as well
# 蒜汁放在里面 一点不会觉得突兀
Garlic sauce in the Zhanshui will not make you feel weird at all
# 这一根面进去 盆里就像少了好多面条一样
It feel there are so many noodles are missing when i finish a noodle
# 平常的话 姑娘吃一根就差不多了 两根都有点撑了
Normally, one noodle is enough for lady, two is full
# 男的 可以多加一根
Man can have one more noodle
# 一根面条1两7
The weight of a noodle is about 1.7 liang85 grams
# 1两7x4根
Multiply by four
# 咱们都是按照我们当地人的饭量做的
We all cook according to food amount of our local people
# 见过最多的人吃几根  最多的能吃16根
How many noodles have you seen people who eat most? 16
# 很胖吗
Is he fat?
# 不胖 个子还没他高
No, not as tall as him
# 特别能吃 一来就是16根
He eat a lot
# 像南方人吃不完这一份
People who from south of China can not finish it
# 他们也就两根就吃撑了
They eat 2 noodles at most
# 咱们当地人就是 基本上4根够吃
Our local people usually eat four noodles
# 4根差不多
About four noodles
# 4根都吃饱了
They will get full with four noodles
# 在咱家吃面就是两怪
There is two strange things in my restaurant
# 一个是 面条宽
First, noodle is widely
# 另一个大老碗  碗盆分不开
Second is Bowls as big as basins
# 12块钱一盆面
12 yuan for a pot of noodle
# 关 注
# 雪 鱼 探 店
Subscribe xueyu
>